Carsten-Rehder-Str. 52 22767 Hamburg

Mobile Phone: + 49 171 8888 999 Email: rick@torbenrick.eu Website: www.torbenrick.eu

Date of birth: September 29, 1962

Nationality: Danish



SUMMARY

Experienced senior executive, both at a strategic and operational level, with strong track record in developing, driving and managing business improvement and development, change management and turn-around.

Have worked with value-adding leadership and transformation creating simultaneous top line and button line growth.

The main drivers have been marketing and sales efficiency, improved customer and employee satisfaction, customer service, product management, cross functional business improvements and culture change.

Experience from management positions in Denmark, Germany and Switzerland.

EXPERIENCE

2009 - Division Director & Group Business

Development Director (DK)

2008 - 2008: Consultancy & Interim Management (DE)

2006 - 2007: Business & Financial Improvement

Director (DK)

1999 - 2006: Chief Operating Officer (DE)

Project Director (DE)

1998 - 1999: Commercial Project Director (CH)

1995 - 1997: Sales Support Director (DK)

Head of Strategic Business Unit (DK)

1990 - 1995: Head of Logistics & procurement (DK)

Managing Director (DK)

Head of Marketing (DK)

1989 - 1990: Project Manager (DK)

1987 - 1989: Project Manager (DK)

Marketing Coordinator (DK)

BOARD - EXPERIENCE

2014 - 2017 Chairman of the Supervisory Board

AnyCom A/S (DK)

BUSINESS ACHIEVEMENTS

By constantly challenging the way things are done combined with the organizational refocusing programs have been the key factors in obtaining the results:

- Significant financial improvement
- Increasing customer base
- Increasing service level customer service
- Increasing customer and employee satisfaction

2009 -

- Due to heavy focus on business drivers reduced cost-to base and increased customer base -EBITDA margin was improved from 2% to 39%
- Customer base increased from 5.500 to 12.200 in a stagnant market
- Market share up from 26% to 49%

2008

 Successful turn-around a high-tech company. Due to heavy focus on business drivers increased EBITDA margin from – 18% to + 10%

2006 - 2007

 Business improvement with a total cash-in of € 85m equalling to 9% of the total cost base

1999 - 2006

- EBITDA increased by 138% from € 29.7m to € 70.6m
- Revenue increased from € 700m to € 1.000m
- Customer base was more than doubled (to 3,4m)
- Customer and employee satisfaction increased significantly
- Best in class customer service

EDUCATION

- M.Sc. (Business Economics)
- Customer Orientation for Value and High Performance Organizations, INSEAD Executive Education

LANGUAGES

Fluent in Danish, German and English

VERDO A/S, RANDERS, DENMARK Energy

Division Director & Group Business Development Director

Since 2009

Division Director responsible for the fiber company Verdo Tele A/S (sales, marketing, customer service, product management, IT & technology) and member of the Executive Management Board of Verdo A/S.

- Due to heavy focus on business drivers reduced cost-base and increased customer base EBITDA margin
 was improved from 2% to 39%. Successful changed the organization to be much more market, sales and
 service oriented
- Customer base increased from 5.500 to 12.200 in a stagnant market market share up from 26% to 49%
- Customer satisfaction increased from index 67 to 85 employee satisfaction increased to index 81 (Top performer)

Group business development director responsible for: Group business development and strategy, business and financial improvement, cross-functional business improvement.

MELIORATE SOLUTION, HAMBURG, GERMANY Interim Management

Consultancy & Interim Management

2008 to 2008

Interim Business Development Advisor, Energy Randers Denmark (Energy industry). Hired by the CEO to evaluate and improve a major strategic project.

Interim Business Development Advisor, Vopium Germany (Mobile VOIP). Hired by the board to develop "routes to market" in Germany.

Interim Business Development & Financial Improvement Executive, Comlog A/S Denmark & Germany (Telematic). Hired by the board and charged with turning around the company which was highly underperforming as to its financial performance and product quality.

Due to heavy focus on business drivers increased EBITDA margin from – 18% to + 10%

TDC A/S, COPENHAGEN, DENMARK Telecommunication

Business & Financial Improvement Director

2006 to 2007

Reporting to the CEO of TDC Solution A/S, responsible for Business & Financial Improvement with 34 employees - Lean Management, Business Process Management and reduction of production and capacity needs.

Total "cash-in" of € 85m equalling to 9% of the total cost base

TALKLINE GMBH & CO. KG, HAMBURG, GERMANY Mobile Telecommunication

Chief Operating Officer

2001 to 2006

Member of the Board of Directors (Geschäftsführung), responsible for 480 employees covering customer service, eBusiness, marketing, product management, procurement and sales with a yearly revenue of € 1.000m

- EBITDA increased by 138% due to heavy focus on customer profitability and efficiency from € 29.7m in 2001 to
 ₹ 70.6m in 2005. EBITDA-margin increased by 82% to 7,0%
- Revenue increased from € 700m to € 1.000m
- Despite getting closer to market saturation the customer base has more than doubled from 1,7 m to 3,4m customers and customer satisfaction increased from index 100 to 124
- Best in class customer service Connect Call Center Test 2001: Best in class, 2002: Second best in class, 2003: Best in class among all German service providers
- Employee satisfaction pushed from index 72 to 83 points

Talkline was sold to competitor Debitel/Mobilcom at € 560m

TALKLINE GMBH & Co. KG, HAMBURG, GERMANY Mobile Telecommunication

Project Director 1999 to 2000

Member of Erweiterte Geschäftsführung (EGF), reporting to the CEO, responsible for business development

- Development and implementation of refocus program (Turn-around/Corporate Transformation) which included Cost Improvement and Revenue Improvement Program
- Successfully implemented Culture Change Program "Wir machen es einfach" (We make it simple)
- Reduced call volume by 35% with a wide range of self-services and churn by 45% with retention/ prevention programs

SUNRISE COMMUNICATIONS AG, ZÜRICH, SWITZERLAND Telecommunication

Commercial Project Director

1998 to 1999

Reporting to the CEO, responsible for business development in a recently established communications company owned by TDC, British Telecom, UBS, Migros and SBB.

- Successful acquisition of an ISP, commercial and legal negotiations, due diligence, business plan and integration
- Successfully acquired Credit Swiss First Boston (London), global customer with an annual revenue of € 13m
- Successfully implemented balanced scorecard and culture program: "Let's follow the sunrise... on a balloon trip around the world"

TDC A/S, AARHUS, DENMARK Telecommunication

Sales Support Director

1997

Head of domestic and international sales support with 72 employees, including 7 function managers.

Responsible for domestic and international pre-sales support, project management, Total Service Management, contract administration, development and implementation of Balanced Scorecard.

- Reengineered the total sales supporting process in TDC
- Raised the professional level of competence in the organisation

Head of Strategic Business Unit

1995 to 1996

Reporting to the Division Director, Total Service Management with 13 employees.

Business and market foundation in the newly established Strategic Business Unit starting from scratch. Responsible for development and implementation of services within IT Facility Management.

Annual sales responsibility of € 13m, responsible for overall marketing strategy, customer and competitor analyses, development of various sales & marketing tools, PR activities, conferences, seminars etc.

DANADATA A/S, AARHUS, DENMARK Information Technology & Services

Head of Logistics & Procurement

1992 to 1995

Reporting to the CFO, responsible for procurement, warehouse, configuration and test center and dealer team with a total of 37 employees.

- Procurement of € 100m distributed on 4,500-5,000 article numbers with an average inventory turnover ratio of 11-12.
- Sale to retailers with an annual sales budget of € 30m.

DANADATA A/S, AARHUS, DENMARK Information Technology & Services

Managing Director 1992 to 1995

Responsible for the distribution company PC Distribution A/S of (50 percent owned by DanaData A/S). International contract negotiations in USA, UK, France and Germany.

Head of Marketing 1990 to 1991

Head of the central marketing department with 4 employees. Overall responsibility for DanaData's operational & strategic marketing.

Responsible for international marketing activities in connection with International Computer Group (ICG) in Paris.

Nykredit, Aarhus, Denmark Building Society - Financial Services

Project Manager 1989 to 1990

Responsible for operational & strategic marketing (B2B) and central sponsoring.

Kreditforeningen Danmark, Copenhagen and Odense, Denmark Building Society - Financial Services

Project Manager 1988 to 1989

Responsible for the project group: "Sales and Marketing" whose purpose was to draw up strategic proposals for the executive committee and the board of directors as part of the planning project "A plan for KD".

Marketing Coordinator 1987 to 1988

Responsible for the decentralised marketing and sponsoring function in the Funen area with 2 employees.

EDUCATION

M.Sc. (Business Economics), Aarhus School of Business (DK)	<i>1987</i>
B.Sc. (Business Economics), Sønderborg School of Business (DK)	<i>1984</i>

SUPPLEMENTRY EDUCATION

Customer Orientation for Value, INSEAD Executive Education (F	F) 2004
High Performance Organizations, INSEAD Executive Education	(F) 2001

PERSONALITY TEST

DISC C, D

Decision Dynamics Role style: Flexible - Operating style: Decisive

HBDI Whole Brain

MBTI ENTJ (Extraversion, Intuition, Thinking, Judgment)

Situational Leadership II Primary leadership style: Supporting

RECOMMENDATIONS

Recommendations - https://www.torbenrick.eu/recommendations/